Denis Haskin

618 Miramar Dr Santa Cruz, CA 95060 781-258-7414 denis@constantorbit.com
 http://constantorbit.com
http://github.com/denishaskin
http://github.com/constantorbit

Summary

Senior technical architect, consultant, and manager with significant design and implementation skills. Proven experience delivering successful, scalable, reliable commercial products. Excellent communication, analysis, leadership, and mentoring skills. Equally comfortable in technical and management roles, startups and enterprises.

Technologies and Practices

Languages	Ruby, Javascript, Coffeescript, Java
Systems	Linux, Mac OS X, Microsoft Windows operating systems.
Technologies and platforms	Ruby on Rails, AngularJS, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Amazon AWS (full range), Heroku, Open-source frameworks and tools, JQuery.
Tools	Rspec, shoulda, Git, Subversion, CI tools, chef
Databases & related technologies	PostgreSQL, MySQL
Practices	Responsive design, Test-driven development, Iterative development, User stories.

Employment History

Consultant/contractor

November 2008 – present

Constant Orbit (sole proprietorship)

Santa Cruz, CA

Advise clients on web application design, scalability, cloud computing, big data, social software, analytics, and e-commerce. Implement applications, consult on technical designs, assist with operations management, advise and mentor on development practices. Clients include a social media monitoring & alerting service startup, online music publishing e-commerce vendor, the pre-eminent Chicago & Los Angeles improv comedy theater, a financial technologies incubator, a multinational engineering software vendor, among others.

Senior Software Developer

May 2015 – August 2016

PredPol, Inc

Santa Cruz, CA

Senior developer in self-managed technology team of the world's leading predictive policing company. Architect and implement solutions at all levels of our stack and all components of our infrastructure (entirely on AWS). Provide direct customer technical support on all aspects of our products. Manage and improve devops tools and processes. Evaluate, select, and implement new, more effective technologies into our stack.

Senior Architect/Technical Lead

Cambridge Systematics

December 2012 - May 2015 Cambridge, MA

Senior technical lead of the software development & consulting unit of transportation consulting firm. Set technology directions for the group, prepare & present RFP responses. Led implementation teams in multiple successful, on-time projects. Mentored junior staff members, demonstrate technical excellence. Provided expert technical support to clients. Championed test-driven design, iterative development and the use of cloud platforms for customer benefit. Strong familiarity with open-source mapping, planning, and routing tools.

СТО November 2009 – December 2015

ZMX Music Newton, MA

Provided initial technology consulting and assistance to company founder, now CTO. Performed all enhancements and maintenance to Ruby on Rails application; migrated it up to current Ruby and Rails versions; converted front-end to Bootstrap and JQuery-based. Integrated with Amazon Payments and Paypal. ZMX Music ceased operation December 2015.

Architect/VP Engineering

January 2010 - July 2011 Boston, MA CargoMetrics Inc.

Founding VPE and technical architect at startup seeking to revolutionize commodity trading through innovative use of transport-related data. Built world-class engineering team from the ground up, responsible for all aspects of implementation and operations. Evaluated, selected, and used leading-edge open-source technologies to build highly scalable, reliable, and secure cloud-based systems and processes to manage, process, and analyze billions of data elements for customers in the financial, energy, and government sectors. Member of senior management staff; primary technical liaison with data partners.

Chief Architect/VP Engineering 2009 - 2010 Fashion Playtes, Inc. Salem, MA

Founding Architect and VPE at Fashion Playtes, startup offering mass customization of pre-teen apparel. Technical architect & primary implementer in small tech team of 2.5, doing the whole range: prototyping, system design, Rails+HTML+CSS coding (plus a small dabbling of Flash/Flex), operations (deployed on AWS), and second-level customer technical support.

Architect & Vice President, Engineering 2008 - 2009 B*Tween Productions, Inc. Lexington, MA

Designed, led implementation of, and managed the operations of a social networking and virtual economy startup for the pre-teen market, developed and deployed on the Amazon AWS cloud computing platform using Ruby on Rails. Product membership at 50,000 users 3 months after launch and growing at just under 4,000 new members per week.

Delivered initial implementation of the product in 3 months with minimal development staff; added virtual economy (with real-currency sales) 2 months later. Hired and managed global virtual team of independent contractors; established and supervised operations and QA.

Director, Business Applications Development 2006 - 2008 NameMedia, Inc. Waltham, MA

Directed 3 teams developing the high-traffic Java-based retail web sites, sales automation, and portfolio management systems supporting the world's largest single portfolio of domain names and one of the major domain name brokerage sites; site achieves millions of dollars in sales per month and supports 70,000 unique daily visitors.

Hired and directed remote team which executed a ground-up re-design and -implementation of the company's domain name analysis, valuation, and acquisition system using a service-oriented architecture to integrate with cross-business-unit retail and brokerage systems. Directed integration of acquired auction platform. Project lead, technical architect, and primary business liaison for major revision of retail web site, pricing, and sales systems, including significant change in business processes. Primary technical member of task force negotiating multi-year contract with one of the world's largest domain name registrars. Technical lead on CRM evaluation. Collaborated closely with operations staff to deliver consistent 99.97%+ uptime. Primary staff member for technical problem escalation.

Software Development Manager 2004 - 2006 Cambridge Systematics, Inc. Cambridge, MA

Led 11-18 member software development group designing, implementing (primarily in Java), and integrating multi-million-dollar transportation-related regulatory, maintenance, planning, and analysis applications for Federal, state, and local clients.

Implemented multi-million-dollar, multi-year web-based commercial-vehicle permit automation systems for New York and Indiana, including significant integration with existing state systems. Key client technical liaison for the Indiana project. Played key role in winning bid for re-implementation of the Pontis bridge-management product (in use by 45 states and foreign jurisdictions) as a .NET web application. Introduced and coached staff on iterative and incremental development, usability analysis, user-centered design, test-driven development, effective unit testing and continuous integration. Relentless focus on testability. Key player in changing project bidding process to involve development staff at all steps of bid analysis and preparation.

Senior/Lead Software Engineer 1999 - 2004 Siebel Systems, Inc. Burlington, MA

Technical lead for 6-10 person team which consistently delivered on-time, successful projects. Provided architectural direction, leadership, and mentoring to the group; worked closely with partners and product managers to define requirements, design solutions, and develop and execute project plans.

Designed architecture and led implementation of the eContent Server which provides Siebel customers with integrated, dynamic, and customizable research information, including news headlines and stories from Lexis-Nexis and company information from MarketGuide and Dun & Bradstreet. Designed and led implementation & validation of training content integration APIs, using the AICC and SCORM industry standards. Designed and led implementation of significant architectural changes to the Consumer Goods trade promotions module. Collaborated closely with Siebel Life Sciences team to architect and implement shared territory management module, including support for versioning and activity assignment. Java, C++, and Perl platforms.

Senior Software Developer 1997 - 1999 The Gale Group, A Thomson Company Cambridge, MA

Designer, lead developer and project manager for an intra-corporate project to host a sister company's data on the Gale Group's proprietary search engine and provide access to it through a Web Services-like interface.

Responsible for all development and maintenance on a C++-based middle-tier server which provided a proprietary interface to a search & retrieval engine. Collaborated with internal partners to design and implement API enhancements to handle new content types and extend the functionality of both the up- and down-stream interfaces.

Senior Manager for Production Engineering 1992 - 1997 The Gale Group, A Thomson Company Cambridge, MA

Managed eleven-member staff to design, implement, maintain, and execute procedures and tools for the Internet, Web, CompuServe, and CD ROM database products. Provided technical leadership and direction to the group.

Designed and led implementation of tools to automatically load data, update indices, perform automatic quality control checks, manufacture 39 CD ROM masters and update 59 online products (combined annual revenue of \$47.5 million) supporting an average of 70,000 sessions per day. Planned, coordinated, and managed projects with customer organizations. Coordinated with other departments, including software tools development, data center support, data asset management.

Director of DR Labs

1988 - 1992

Digital Review , Ziff-Davis/Cahners Publishing

Boston and Newton, MA

Managed four technical analysts and one systems support staff for magazine covering Digital Equipment Corporation and related third-party market. Served as lead technical resource for editorial and marketing staff. Wrote and edited articles (both product reviews and news articles) and directed copyflow. Designed and implemented performance benchmarking software and procedures in C++ and C.

Manager of Technical Services

1984 - 1988

Clark University

Worcester, MA

Directed design, implementation, and maintenance of all systems and applications software. Supervised operation and management of all hardware and software components of the University's campus network. Coordinated implementation of the University's campus-wide administrative information system. Supervised two programmer/analysts and four system operators. Managed and provided advanced technical consulting and programming support for the 2,500 members of the University's academic and administrative communities.

Publications

• Freelance writer from 1987 to 1999 for several magazines, including *Digital Review*, *Unix Review*, *Byte*, *Corporate Computing*, *Back-Office Magazine*.

Education

- **BA in Computer Science** (minor in Music Theory), *cum laude*; elected to Phi Beta Kappa in junior year. Clark University, Worcester, MA
- Jakarta International School, Jakarta, Indonesia